[theme music playing]
So you're the one
tutoring my son for free.
You're more beautiful up close.
[Arthur] Did your wife tell you
about what happened yesterday at school?
[Dante] I'll press charges!
[Camia] Please don't stir up trouble.
[Cindy] Slow down, I might slip.
-[Raul] Take your shoes off.
-[Cindy] It's slippery.
[tense music playing]
-[Cindy] What is it?
-[gunshot]
-[man 1] The job's done.
-[Emilia] Good job.
Poor Cinderella.
[Julio] It's the talk of the town.
Your devoted husband couldn't
keep his pants on again.
Fix this, Emilia.
Our political enemies
might catch wind of this.
-Yes, Papa.
-That Dante Cruz…
He has already aggravated
a friend of mine from Manila.
He's not easy to silence.
[Emilia] I'll take care of him, Papa.
[man] Attorney Cruz, the mayor
is inviting you to her office.
-I'm not afraid of you!
-You won't win.
[vehicle crashes]
You killed my husband! Get out!
[Diego crying] Lily, I'm sorry.
I don't know. I'm sorry, Lily.
[Camia] Who are you?
Don't come any closer.
-[Lily] Mom?
-[Camia] Get out of here.
Hey!
Lily… Run!
-No!
-[gunshot]
[sobbing] Help… Help me!
Mom. Mom. Mom. Mom!
Mom!
[woman] No, sir. I didn't hear
any gunshot or screaming.
We didn't hear anything.
[police officer] Nothing?
You didn't see anyone come here?
No.
Good morning.
I'm Esther from the social
welfare department.
-And he's my colleague.
-Good morning, sir.
We were sent here for a
child named… Lily Cruz.
[suspenseful music playing]
-I don't think I can do this.
-This isn't the first time.
You know I don't kill children, right?
How about you? Can you kill her?
Let's just set her free!
The governor and mayor
will kill us if we let her go.
Then think of another way!
[whispers] I can't do this.
[man] Don't tell me
you're feeling guilty now.
[tense music playing]
-Oh, no!
-What?
-[man] Lily!
-Lily!
-Lily! Lily!
-[man] Stop right there!
-[Esther] Lily!
-[man] Come back!
-Got you!
-Please let go!
-Where are you going?
Hello, Mayor. Should I dump the body?
-[goon 1] There's a car!
-[goon 2] Relax.
-Do you have the child?
-Yes, ma'am.
I want to hear her.
Please don't kill me!
Please have mercy on me.
-[Lily] I'm begging you.
-Hello?
You know what to do. Finish her off.
[sobbing] Please let me go!
Mister, don't kill me.
[gunshot]
-[slow instrumental music playing]
-[rain pouring]
[sobbing]
Get up. Listen.
You have to get away from here. Go.
[man] Just don't tell the police.
Don't tell anyone. No matter what happens…
don't ever come back
to Poblacion Ardiente.
Understood?
-Hurry! Run!
-[Esther] Go now!
-[man] Alma…
-[Alma] Yes?
[man] I need another basket
for my next trip here.
[Alma] Okay.
[man] Is that everything, Philip?
Let's get the rest so we can leave soon.
[ambulance siren wailing]
[tense music playing]
[man] I like that tree's fruits.
-[Alma] Okay. Take care.
-[man] See you.
[engine roaring]
[Loring] It's deserted. What happened?
Diego, don't go in there! Just stay here.
Why is it closed off?
Oh, hey! Excuse me, miss!
-Do you know what happened here?
-We aren't sure, either.
They didn't see a body
or anything. Nothing at all.
Where's Mrs. Camia?
It's been two days,
but we haven't even caught
a glimpse of her.
-I think she's dead.
-No. No. Don't say that!
-What about Lily?
-[woman] Oh, Lily.
The social workers
took her away yesterday.
Back to Manila.
[Raul's phone ringing]
-Hey, Diego.
-[Diego crying] Daddy?
-We're at Lily's.
-[Raul] Didn't I tell you
not to go to that place anymore?
There's tape that says
"Police Line Do Not Cross" here.
I'm worried that Mrs. Camia may be dead.
Lily's gone too.
The social workers took her to Manila.
-They took her to Manila right away?
-[Diego] Yes.
Daddy, you know a lot of cops, right?
Let's find Lily.
I'm sure she needs our help right now.
You know, Diego…
It's better if…
you don't expect to see Lily again.
What?
[melancholic music playing]
He said I won't see Lily again.
[slow upbeat music playing]
[street noise]
[indistinct chatter]
We need to hurry up, okay?
What the heck is this?! Who are you?!
For Pete's sake! That's been weighed!
-[Lily] I'm sorry, sir.
-Explain this to my boss!
I'm really sorry! I didn't mean to!
-Hey, come back here! Hey, kid!
-I'm really sorry, sir!
[Lily panting]
Kid.
Need a ride? Where to?
I don't.
Sir… Can I ask you something?
Do you know the way to San Marcelino?
-How do I get there?
-Of course, I do!
Can you please tell me how to get there?
I'll walk to it.
-It's too far! You'll get lost.
-I don't have money.
Just tell me how to get there.
[tricycle driver] It's all right.
I can walk.
You'll get lost!
It's all right! Hop in, come on.
-Mister, what is this place?
-Wait here.
-Why, what's happening?
-I need to get something.
Are we there yet? Get what?
I'll just get something. Move a little.
-Sir, I have to go.
-Stay. It won't take long.
-I don't?
-Stay. Let's talk a bit.
I thought you were getting something.
I'm tired. Let's rest here.
I'll get off here. I'll just walk.
-You smell like mangoes.
-[Lily] What? Are you okay?
[tricycle driver] This won't take long.
Hey!
Hey! Get away from me, please. Hey!
-[Lily] Mom, what happened to you?
-[Camia shushes]
-Hey!
-[Camia] Hurry!
-Mister, let go of me!
-Come on, kid.
Let go of me.
Mister, I'm going to go down!
[tricycle driver] Come on.
[screams] Mom!
-Stay here!
-No! Please!
-Get in.
-Let me go!
[tricycle driver] You're a fighter, huh?
[Jepoy blows whistle loudly]
[dramatic music playing]
[Jepoy blows whistle]
Are you okay?
Obviously, you're not.
[quiet music playing]
-Come here.
-Don't touch me!
Suit yourself, you snob!
[Jepoy blows whistle]
Here. Put that on.
I'll help you out. You really are a snob.
There are lots of thugs around here.
Here.
If you're in trouble, blow this.
Anyway, I gotta go. I'm the parking boy!
Jepoy. Just ask around, they know me!
[sullen music playing]
[sobbing]
[car horn honking]
-[sobbing]
-[car horns honking]
-[car horn honking]
-[tires squealing]
[Emilia] Leave the bags there.
Shopping spree?
I was stressed.
Why? Is your conscience getting to you?
You're sick.
You killed them all off? A whole family?
Isn't that what you wanted?
I'm just being a good wife.
Diego said social workers
picked up the kid, Lily.
Were they really? Or was that another job?
[exhales]
Can you please stop acting
like you have a conscience?
Because it doesn't suit you!
Are you still human?
You didn't even spare the kid.
You don't have the right
to lecture me about a conscience!
Don't be a hypocrite
because you're just as guilty!
And besides, you should be happy
because that family's all together now.
[slow instrumental playing]
[car horn honking]
[panting]
[chuckles]
Thank goodness you're awake.
Uh… I'm Carlotta, by the way.
Ms. Prianka said you weren't hurt,
you just fainted.
Okay, I'll let you eat first.
I'll check back on you later.
[suspenseful music playing]
How are you feeling?
[sighs]
I'm asking you how you're feeling.
Oh, well.
I won't waste my time on someone
who doesn't want to talk.
-[stutters] I have to go.
-Go ahead.
The doors are wide open.
You didn't run me over?
No.
You passed out right on time.
Probably because of hunger,
or because of--
You smell awful.
When was the last time you took a bath?
-[comical music playing]
-[Prianka exhales]
Excuse me, I need air.
[slow instrumental playing]
Sweetie, ma'am asked you to take a shower
and brush your teeth.
I'll get you a change of clothes.
[water dripping]
[dramatic music playing]
[Camia] We'll go away.
That's what we should do.
-[Camia] Lily… Run!
-[Lily crying] Mom.
[Lily] Get off me! Help! Help!
Mom…
Little girl? I'm coming in.
Are you crying?
What happened to you? Hold on.
-Don't touch me!
-Wait, it's okay! It's okay.
Get away! Please let me go!
-What's happening here?
-Let me go…
[whimpering]
-[Carlotta] Hush now.
-[hallucinating] Mom. Dad.
Mom.
[Carlotta humming]
[Carlotta shushes]
I'll take care of her, Carlotta.
-Ma'am?
-I can look after a kid, Carlotta.
Mom.
Ardiente. Ardiente.
Ardiente.
Mayor.
Governor Ardiente.
-[Prianka] It's okay.
-Ardiente. The Ardientes…
[dramatic music playing]
[slow instrumental music playing]
[water dripping]
Mom?
I'm not your mother.
Thank you for taking care of me.
-You're really kind.
-[scoffs]
I'm not kind.
I just don't want anyone
dying on my watch.
[Carlotta clears throat]
-You're in charge of her.
-Yes, ma'am.
Are you feeling better?
Hmm?
Come here.
Let's lift your head a little. That's it.
Just a sip, sweetie.
[Loring] Finish your food
before they arrive. You know how it is.
Thanks, Nanny.
Whenever I think about Lily…
I just get hungrier.
Why don't the social workers
in Manila know where Lily is?
I don't know, either.
Now finish your food.
We'll call them again later.
[cheerful music playing]
-Nanny!
-[Loring] Yes?
I know how to find Lily!
Come with me, quick!
Okay.
[Diego on television] My name is…
Diego Ardiente-Torillo.
I'm the son of Mayor Emilia,
and the grandson of Governor Julio.
I called social services in Manila.
My best friend Lily Cruz
isn't there either.
To the people who know where Lily is,
please call me
or my nanny at 627-3256.
Lily, I'm really worried.
Come back to Poblacion Ardiente.
[Prianka] Murderous social workers?
[Lily crying] Yes, I heard them talk.
It was Mayor Emilia who wanted me killed.
I think they let me escape
because they felt sorry for me.
I came to Manila to find my uncle.
[stutters] But…
But the tricycle driver…
-[sobbing] The driver…
-[shushes]
[Carlotta] Just stay here, dear.
It's too dangerous for you to go back.
You're safe here, okay?
[Emilia] Don't worry.
I assure you I spoke
to that child Lily Cruz myself.
Yes. Thank you. Goodbye.
That was the head
of social services in Manila.
They're trying to trace
where Lily Cruz is,
because of what your son did!
Now we're involved in a scandal.
That issue should've died already!
Good afternoon, Grandpa.
-You idiot!
-What did I do, Grandpa?
You caused a huge scandal!
Because of you,
people are talking about a child
who's gone missing
from Poblacion Ardiente!
-And you.
-[Diego crying]
I'm talking to you! Stand up.
Aren't you using your brain?!
Didn't you realize
you could get us all in trouble
by going to the TV station?
-But sir--
-Huh?
[Loring whimpering]
Why are your eyes closed? Open your eyes.
Open them! Open them!
-So you can see where this comes from!
-[Diego] Grandpa!
[Julio] All you two ever bring is trouble!
-[Loring squealing]
-[Diego] Stop it, Grandpa!
Huh?
-You two belong together!
-Grandpa.
-[Loring squealing]
-[Diego wailing]
Papa, that's enough! Your heart!
You looked pathetic asking
for help on national television!
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
Diego! You don't get it, do you?
You always bring disgrace to this family!
Why did you even mention
you were an Ardiente?!
Because that's my last name.
Because of what you did,
we are involved in a crime.
I really don't understand
how you can be an Ardiente.
You're the only disgrace to this family.
[Diego wailing]
That's enough. Come here. Stand up.
[Diego sobbing]
Don't cry.
Take care of him.
Go.
[sullen music playing]
[Diego coughing]
Seriously? Are you crying again?
It's true! You don't act like an Ardiente.
There's no weak Ardiente.
I was born an Ardiente. I am an Ardiente.
And I'm going to prove it.
[Arnaldo] Sure!
After you stop being fat.
[Julio] I really don't understand
how you can be an Ardiente.
You're the only disgrace to this family.
[Arnaldo] There is no weak Ardiente.
[Diego] I'm an Ardiente,
and I'm going to prove it.
Thank you for everything.
But I need to go.
Then what?
You'll go back to Poblacion Ardiente?
I need to know what happened to my mother.
Don't you know what happened to your mom?
She's dead.
She was killed by the same
people that wanted you dead.
[crying] That's not true!
She's still alive! I can feel it!
When I go back,
I'll know what happened to her.
-When I go back--
-When you go back,
you'll be murdered.
You'll suffer the same fate
as your mother.
Maybe worse than your mother.
So stop it, Lily. Your mom is dead.
That's not true!
You don't know what you're saying!
You don't know anything! That's not true!
You don't know anything!
[Lily sobbing]
Come with me.
[Carlotta] Ms. Prianka.
-Come!
-[Lily] Please let me go.
[Carlotta] Ms. Prianka.
Have mercy on her. Ms. Prianka.
Look! That's the grave of my daughter!
Yes, that's my child!
She died because I wanted justice
for the assassination of my husband.
I went to war unprepared.
And until now, I cannot forgive myself
for the death of my daughter.
[sobbing]
So don't you dare tell me
I don't know anything.
This is what I know.
You can't go back to Ardiente
while you're still weak.
You need to be ready
and strong when you face them.
Your mom and dad are both dead, Lily.
[whimpers]
Whether you like it or not,
you have to accept that.
Now, I ask you.
What do you want?
Do you want to follow them to the grave?
[pensive music playing]
So, what do you want, Lily? Is that it?
I want to make them pay
for what they did to us.
I can't hear you.
I want to make the Ardientes
pay for what they did to us.
I still can't hear you.
I want justice for my mom and dad!
Again?
I want justice for my parents!
Good.
Then we have a deal.
[dramatic music playing]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Lily] The Count of Monte Cristo.
It's my favorite book.
[instrumental theme music playing]
-[Lily] 365 Days?
-For a year filled with love.
[instrumental theme music playing]
Mom…
Dad…
[instrumental theme music playing]
That's it. Cry it all out.
Bury your memories of them.
If you want my help,
you will do what I say.
[exhales] I will.
Put all of them in the box.
[sobbing]
Now!
[sobs]
[dramatic music playing]
[Prianka] Bury it.
Now!
Wipe your tears. Stop crying!
[Lily] What is this?
Open and read it.
I'm keeping my end of the bargain.
I've legally adopted you.
You'll be called… Ivy Aguas.
[quiet music playing]
From now on, that is your birthday.
The day you arrived in my house.
-Uh…
-A simple thank you will do.
[stutters] Thank you.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Carlotta chuckles]
[Prianka] Make sure to do me proud.
Don't let me down
because you carry my name.
Something grew.
Yes.
A lone blossom.
A wildflower.
[Ivy] What's it called?
I don't know.
But that's not important.
What's important
is it can thrive anywhere.
It can survive
in the midst of any weather…
with no one taking care of it.
It doesn't let the world bring it down.
[instrumental theme music playing]
And I hope you grow up to be like one.
First, a napkin.
It's very important to keep
your posture straight at all times.
These are for water,
red wine, and white wine.
For the appetizer… For the soup.
No, Ivy. This way.
Good, right?
Go! Go, Ivy!
[Ivy] This was the only way
for me to be reborn.
To fulfill my new dreams.
Become a new me.
[Prianka] There.
Change! Protect yourself.
[Ivy] There are times
I still think about them…
or dream of seeing them,
even in a picture.
I'm scared that I might forget
their faces,
the memories of my family.
But Ms. Prianka did say that,
if I want justice…
I need to be patient.
[tense music playing]
[boy grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[both grunt]
[guy groans]
Proud of yourself, are you?
Were you expecting me to applaud you?
You should know better, Ivy.
Get dressed. We're leaving.
There are a lot of things
you still have to learn.
[slow beat playing]
-Good morning, ma'am!
-[guard] Good morning, ma'am.
Everyone, attention please.
I want to introduce you
all to my daughter, Ivy.
Starting today, she'll work
every day here after school.
[all] Good morning, Ms. Ivy!
I don't want any special treatment.
Just Ivy.
[woman] Are you grooming
your daughter, ma'am?
Retiring anytime soon?
No. Perhaps you'll retire first.
[woman] I was just kidding, ma'am.
Good morning. The meeting
is ready in 15 minutes at the board room.
That's the bidding for the C5 project.
I want you with me.
Ivy? What are you waiting for? Now!
Mr. De Leon,
our last bid is 88 million pesos.
Ms. Aguas, there are
developments in the area.
In the north side,
they established a mall.
And in the south side,
there will be a rail transit
in a prime location.
What I am saying, Ms. Aguas,
is that my property is really huge.
And you're offering me
much less than what it's worth.
It's our last bid,
Mr. De Leon. Take it or leave it.
There are six other companies
that are bidding on my company.
But I'm looking for
a more permanent relationship.
I mean, a business
partnership with your company.
I don't do partnerships.
I never believed in forever.
It's never too late to believe in forever.
Why don't we just schedule
another meeting between the two of us?
I'll think about it.
Frankly, I don't see any point.
Unless you give me a very good reason.
Thank you very much
for your time, Mr. De Leon.
I wish you good luck
with your six bidders.
My next meeting is waiting. Excuse me.
[slow beat playing]
[secretary] Ma'am,
we didn't close the deal.
The contractor is ready.
Hold this.
Five. Four.
-Three. Two.
-[phone ringing]
Answer it.
-Hello, Mr. De Leon?
-Hello. May I speak
to Ms. Aguas, please?
Because I'll never forgive myself
if I let go of the chance
to work with someone as
beautiful as you.
Okay. Meet me at my house, 8 PM.
-Don't be late.
-I'll be there.
You'll be there too.
[slow beat playing]
Thank you for having me
for dinner, Ms. Aguas.
Mr. De Leon, call me Prianka.
Then you can call me Teddy.
[chuckles softly]
Sure, Teddy Boy. Have a seat.
Thank you.
Oysters?
They say eating oysters
on an empty stomach is not a good idea.
[Prianka laughs]
Casanova, the greatest lover,
loved eating oysters for breakfast.
It was his favorite aphrodisiac.
[sensual music playing]
Then, I better have an oyster.
[slurps]
[Prianka] We've had three meetings.
I don't think you want to make me feel
that you're just messing around,
Teddy Boy.
Because you know
I hate wasting time.
I'm the same way.
[chuckles]
[Prianka] I believe that
when you know what you want,
you should know how to get it.
What do you want, Teddy Boy?
More oysters?
Yes.
[clicks tongue]
As for me…
This is what I want.
Of course.
[slow beat playing]
It was good
doing business with you, Mr. De Leon.
I'm sorry, I have another meeting.
Ivy will show you the way out.
After you finish your dinner, of course.
[Ivy] She got what she wanted
at a price she dictated
without a compromise.
She put herself out there like bait.
But didn't fall for her own trap.
That came from the projection
studies prepared by Ivy.
Well?
Uh, Ms. Prianka, based on the analyses--
Well… Those analyses are obviously wrong.
I'm sorry.
Sorry is the most meaningless word for me.
Do you know what I'd appreciate more?
If you work harder.
Try it.
[Ivy] Sometimes, I admire her.
Other times, she frustrates me.
But now…
I want to be just like her.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Ivy] And that will ensure
the success of this project.
So, where do I sign, Ms. Aguas?
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
♪ Let her cry, for she's a lady
For she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream, for she's a child
For she's a child ♪
♪ Let the rain
Let the rain fall down upon her ♪
[Mia] Didn't I say no?
Quit bothering me! I said no!
[man] You don't have to pretend.
-[Mia] Stop!
-[man] I know you want it too.
-[Mia] I don't! Stop!
-[man] Come on!
-[man] You want this, right?
-[Mia] I don't!
-You want this too, don't you?
-Stop it! Get off me!
[Ivy] If Mia says she doesn't want to…
-[man] Ouch. Ma'am.
-That means no! Understood?
[Ivy] Mia? Go back to work.
-Yes, ma'am.
-And you? You're fired.
[groans]
-Guard!
-That hurts.
Take him outside.
Starting today,
he is no longer our employee.
All right, ma'am. Come here.
-Ma'am?
-Yes?
I wanted to thank you
for saving me earlier.
Mia, having good manners is important.
But I'd like it more if you
learned to defend yourself.
We women shouldn't wait
for a knight in shining armor.
Learn how to protect yourself.
Yes, ma'am.
You may go.
[Ivy] Ms. Prianka always said…
that one should be patient
to achieve justice.
I have to wait for the right moment.
I've waited for so long.
And even though the whole world
knows me as Ivy Aguas…
a different name…
with a different origin…
and a different birthday…
Lily isn't dead.
She's been waiting
for the right moment to strike.
Happy birthday, Lily.
[instrumental theme music playing]
Ivy? You're home early.
You're leaving, Ms. Prianka?
Do you want me to accompany you?
No. I'll be fine.
-Nanny Carlotta?
-Yes?
Do you know where Ms. Prianka is going?
-She didn't come to work today.
-She didn't say.
Only that it was a personal trip.
But, you know, it's been going
on for six months now.
She leaves every Thursday without fail.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Emilia] My condolences,
Mrs. Cruz. I'm sorry for your loss.
It must've been so painful for you.
-Get out of here!
-Mom! Please stop!
[Camia] You killed my husband!
You killed my husband!
-[shushes]
-[man] Hey!
Run!
Mom?
[Carlotta] Ms. Prianka? Ms. Prianka?
Ms. Prianka? Ms. Prianka?
Ivy! Ivy!
-Nanny Carlotta?
-[Carlotta crying] Ivy!
What happened?
Ms. Prianka? Ms. Prianka?! Ms. Prianka?
Ms. Prianka?
She has Stage IV ovarian
cancer. She was diagnosed too late.
She refuses to have regular check-ups,
even though she's shown
symptoms for months.
[doctor] It's been six months
since she was diagnosed with cancer.
We do chemotherapy every Thursday,
but she refuses to stay in the hospital.
[coughs]
[wheezing]
[somber music playing]
[coughs]
[weakly] You know…
you've been a good child.
That's the first time you praised me.
[Prianka] Ivy.
I may not show it…
but I love you as my own daughter.
For a long time…
you gave me purpose…
to keep living.
But now, I can finally let go.
No. Ms. Prianka, no.
No, no.
[sighs heavily]
You can't give up.
You said you don't want
anyone dying on your watch.
So, you can't give up. You can't die.
There is no point, Ivy.
Death is inevitable.
I've kept my end of the deal.
Now…
it's your turn.
Remember everything I taught you.
Do what you must do.
[shushes]
Make them pay.
-Ms. Prianka? Ms. Prianka?
-[Prianka groaning]
Ma'am?
Where does it hurt?
Ms. Prianka?
Ma'am? Ms. Prianka?
Ma'am?
[sniffles]
[Ivy] I made a promise to my parents.
Now, I promise you.
I'll make them pay.
[dramatic music playing]
[Ivy] Hello, Poblacion Ardiente.
I'm back.
Who's that?
[Ivy] To all of them, Lily is dead.
[Carlotta] Ivy is here to seek
justice for Lily's parents.
[Ivy] Emilia is the key
to what happened to Mom.
But you are the key to Emilia.
I'll start with you.
[townspeople cheering]
[Diego] I still believe
that Lily will come back.
For you.
[theme music playing]